# 家家户户都会做
Every household knows how to cook this dish
# 家户户做法还不一样
Yet everyone cooks it differently
# 它有很多细节
A lot of detail goes into this
# 你要真正能把它做好 不容易
It’s not easy to cook it really well
# 啥子菜嘞 我看一下我猜一下
What dish is this, let me take a guess
# 这个是个坐板肉 有郫县豆瓣 哦
This is a cut from the gluteal area and Pixian bean paste, oh I know!
# 回锅肉
Hui Guo Rou!
# 我今天选的是地道 传统 正宗的
Today I’ve chosen the most authentic and traditional
# 回锅肉做的 后臀尖
Huiguorou cooked with a gluteal cut of pork
# 它的后臀尖有个特点
One characteristic about gluteal cut
# 肥的比较多 瘦的比较结实
It has more fat portion with burly lean portion
# 现在很多人就用
Nowadays many would use
# 五花肉去做回锅肉 也可以
Pork belly to cook Huiguorou, that works too
# 它是肥瘦相间 口感也还好
It has interlaced fat and lean portion with alright texture
# 但是我们比较传统的
But our version is more traditional
# 还真的是后臀尖
It's really the tip of the hip
# 这叫坐板肉 猪屁股蛋儿那块肉
This is called Zuo ban meat, pork hip meat
# 把锅烧热了
Heat the wok
# 然后现在把这个呲一下
Now singe this a bit
# 这个锅温度还是不要特别高了
The temperature of this wok shouldn't be too high
# 呲一下之后不扒锅
After singeing the pork, the wok becomes non stick
# 但是同时又把上面的猪毛都呲掉了
And at the same time the pig hair on it was singed off
# 然后这个时候
Then this time
# 稍微把它改一改刀
Change it slightly
# 把它切的规整一点 也不要切的太小
Cut it into a smaller size and don’t cut it too small
# 这个一定要用凉水下锅
You must use a pot of cold water for this
# 葱段 姜片 花雕酒
Scallion, sliced ginger, Huadiao wine
# （开锅）煮十分钟
(Boiling) Cook for ten to twenty minutes
# 到二十分钟时间就可以了
# 要煮到这个肉有点溏心
Cook till the inside of the pork is still a bit soft
# 有点溏心有点硬
A bit soft and a bit hard
# 这样的话待会煮出来肉是脆脆的
That way the meat is crispy once cooked
# 一切一煸它就卷起来了 灯盏窝
It rolls up as soon as everything is stirred up, becomes dengzhanwo
# 千万不要用冻肉 冻肉肉发死
Never use frozen meat
# 回锅肉正宗的就是蒜苗
The authentic twice-cooked pork is garlic sprouts
# 我们这么拍一拍 拍松
Let's take a squash like this
# 斜刀切 入味这么着
Cut it in an angle, this helps the flavour to get in
# 一个是入味
For one it helps the flavour to get in
# 待会炒的时候它能散开
Another purpose is to make it separate when cooking
# 然后叶子也是 叶子也很关键
The leaves are also the key
# 这样的蒜苗炒的回锅肉才香
The twice-cooked pork fried with garlic sprouts is fragrant
# 每家每户做的不一样
Every household does it differently
# 今天我还加了一个
I also added one today
# 二荆条
Er Jin Tiao chilli
# 中间切开就好了
Just cut in the middle
# 家庭里面的切法
This is the family style of cutting
# 我再配个颜色好不好
Let me add another colour what do you say
# 红的（小米辣）漂亮
Red (spicy millet), beautiful
# 现在开锅了 把这血沫给它打了
Now it's boiling, skim the scum
# 这血沫不打的话
If you don't remove the scum,
# 待会就贴在肉上 脏
It sticks on the meat later, dirty
# 花椒放一点
Put a little of Sichuan pepper
# 这个时候放
Put it in at this time
# 如果（早放）打血沫就打走了
If (put it in early) the pepper will be taken away while you skim the scum
# 加花椒是去腥增香
Adding pepper is to remove porky smell and enhance fragrance
# 杨兵 肉好了没 好了
Yang bing is the pork ready? Yes it is
# 煮了大概有二十多分钟
Cooked for about 20 minutes
# 筷子刚好插的进去
The chopsticks can easily poke in
# 拉出来之后有一点点的血沫出来
A little bit of blood came out after pulling it out
# 就煮到它的溏心 九成熟
Just boil it until it’s tender on the inside
# 稍微晾一晾 这时候脆的 有弹性
Let it dry for a while, then it's crispy and elastic
# 现在是皮往我这个方向去切
Now I cut the skin in my direction
# 如果你待会炒要打卷的话
If you want to stir-fry later and come out curly
# 千万不能斜着切
Never cut diagonally
# 你觉得要把它切大一点点 就不行了
You think it won’t work if you cut it a little bit bigger
# 就正常正着切 又不能太厚
It's normal and straight and not too thick
# 你看这就是溏心
You see, this is the tender inside
# 里面有一点点的不熟
A little bit uncooked on the inside
# 没这溏心就不好吃 而且还不容易卷
It doesn’t taste good without this and won’t curl up
# 够一份了吧
Enough for one dish
# 这个时候放点油
Put some oil at this time
# 不要让它太高的温度 放肉
Don't let it too high temperature, put the meat
# 卷了卷了
Rolled up
# 灯盏窝起来了
The Dengzhanwo is forming up
# 这个时候放点姜蒜片子
Put some ginger and garlic slices at this time
# 豆瓣酱来它一勺 放在这中间
A spoonful of bean paste and put it in the middle
# 中间的温度比较高
The temperature in the middle is relatively high
# 豆瓣酱一定要通过油的高温
The bean paste must be cooked under the high temperature of the oil
# 去把它煸透了
Go and stir it up thoroughly
# 灯盏窝打卷了吧 颜色出来之后
Dengzhanwo is rolled up, right after the color comes out
# 直接放点干豆豉就好了
Just put some Douchi (Chinese fermented black beans)
# 香味出来之后放一点甜面酱
Put a little Tianmianjiang（sweet wheat paste） after the aroma comes out
# 这个非常关键甜面酱
This is very important Tianmianjiang
# 不搁它不出这酱香味
Without it you won’t smell the saucy aroma
# 刚才不是咱们有辣椒吗
Didn't we have chili just now?
# 辣椒要先下 四川的二荆条
Chili must be cooked first
# 稍微把辣椒的味道刚好闻出来之后
Just after you can smell the chili flavour
# 放蒜苗的梗 它不是偏厚吗
The stalk of the garlic sprouts is thicker, isn’t it?
# 煸炒一下 蒜苗放完之后
Stir fry the garlic sprouts
# 放一点白糖 非常非常关键
Put in a little bit of sugar is very, very important
# 然后放一点点的味精 味精适量
Then add a little bit of MSG, the right amount of MSG
# 来一点酱油
Some soy sauce
# 这个烹酱油也很关键
This cooking soy sauce is also very important
# 是师父教我的
Master taught me
# 酱油和醋一定要烹是吧
Soy sauce and vinegar must be cooked, right?
# 烹了香
Cooking brings out its aroma
# 回锅肉香喷喷的出锅啦
The twice-cooked pork comes out deliciously
# 又香又好吃的回锅肉 好看
Fragrant and delicious twice-cooked pork
# 回锅肉这么一炒
Stir-fry twice-cooked pork like this
# 花花绿绿的漂亮哦 非常漂亮
Colorful and beautiful, very beautiful
# 好吃
Delicious!
# 怎么样 这回锅肉做的地道
How about it? This is made authentically
# 安逸
Comfortable!
# 咸淡正合适
Salty is just right
# 肉炒的跟灯盏似的
The meat is fried like a dengzhan
# 牛
Good job!
# 我说一下
Let me briefly talk about this
# 这个回锅肉 颜色漂亮
This twice cooked pork is beautiful in color
# 刀工精细
Finely cut
# 炒的菜巴巴适适
Stir-fry process is also executed very well
# 这个味道非常安逸
This taste is very good
# 杨兵 给你一个赞
Yang Bing, give you a like
# 给你两个赞
Give you two likes
# 三个赞 谢谢干爹
Three likes, thank you Gan Die
# 下次再来一个 要得
Come to cook again next time, for sure!
# 一会可以吃饭了
I can eat in a while
# 好香哦
So fragrant
# 想请大爷二伯多分享一些
I want to ask Da Ye and Er Bai to share more
# 对传统菜品的定义概念
About the definition of traditional dishes
# 现在的菜品太多
There are too many dishes now
# 没有传统概念了
No more traditional concepts
# 越来越偏
More and more biased
# 我觉得这个网友提的（问题）也非常专业
I think the (question) raised by this netizen is also very professional
# 就是他一眼能看出问题
He can see the problem at a glance
# 我们 跟大爷参加工作
(From the date) Da Ye and I started working as a chef
# 三四十年的光阴了 那时候菜
It has been 30, 40 years. Back then those dished
# 包括我们的站姿
Including our standing posture
# 包括我们从刀工的处理
And knife skills, ingredient handling
# 到最后菜给成形
To the end forming the dish
# 一招一式严格按照师父这种规矩去做
Follow Master’s rules one by one
# 就是切葱
For example chopping green onions
# 现在的宫保鸡丁
Kung Pao Chicken nowadays
# 你看外边全是葱轱辘
Look, the outside is full of green onions
# 过去是不允许的
Was not allowed in the past
# 大爷知道
Da Ye knows
# 都得劈开了
You will have to split it into half
# 我跟大爷做老饭骨一年多
Da Ye and I have been working on this channel for more than a year
# 到今天 有生之年
With all the knowledges we’ve learnt so far
# 把我们四十多年的所学的这些东西
The skills and knowledges we’ve learnt over the 40+ years
# 老师父传承的这些东西
Knowledges passed down from masters
# 结合师父教的
Combined with what the master taught
# 结合我们自己的经验
Combine our own experience
# 尽可能的
As much as possible
# 我们把传承的好的这种技艺
We have inherited this good skill
# 做事 做得规规矩矩的
Do things well
# 给传承下来
To pass down
# 我们五千年的饮食文化
Our five thousand years of food culture
# 走到今天
Till today
# 我不希望在我们这代人身上去断送了
I don’t want to ruin it on our generation
# 对丢的太多了 不行
Right, we lost too much, not acceptable
# 现在餐饮是个乱象
Now the food industry is a mess
# 从学校
From school
# 他完全不是按照过去师父教出
He didn’t follow the previous master’s teaching at all
# 基本原理基本功去传承
Basic principles and basic skills to inherit
# 一上来就是摆盘
It teaches you about plating from the first lesson
# 其实你摆盘摆不好
Actually, you can’t perform the plating well
# 完全按照西餐挺大的一盘
It's quite a big plate exactly as Western food
# 你看没什么东西是吧
You don’t see much, right
# 中不中西不西
(The style is )not Chinese nor Western
# 其实把我们的文化给糟蹋了
Actually ruined our culture
# 所以说真是一个可悲的事
So it's really a sad thing
# 你比如说拆烩鲢鱼头
For example, the split braised silver carp head
# 大爷就完全按照过去
Da Ye just follow the old tradition
# 他的师父那种手法
The way his master does
# 传承下来在基础上有所创新
Inheritance and innovation on the basis
# 但是这创新它是有根基的
But this innovation has a foundation
# 是两方面菜的结合
Is a combination of two styles
# 这种创新
This innovation
# 他又符合川菜这个特点
It matches with the characteristics of Sichuan cuisine
# 我们要做
If we were to do
# 我们就老老实实的
We will be honest
# 我们不会做的
If we don’t know how to do
# 我们绝对不会误导别人
We will never mislead others
# 这是老饭骨的宗旨
This is the purpose of Lao Fan Gu
# 第一我们是传承
First, we inherit
# 第二我们是良心
Second we have conscience
# 第三是责任
The third is responsibility
# 第四我们要求有好的品质
Fourth, we require good quality
# 所以说您刚才今天
So just as you said today
# 给到咱们传统菜品的定义概念
Give us the definition of traditional dishes
# 首先有一个关键词就是要规矩
First of all, there is a key word that is rules
# 对  好
Yes good
# 不管专业厨师和网友
Regardless of professional chefs and netizens
# 爱好美食的
Food-loving
# 擅做美食的
Good at cooking
# 从专业术语角度说
From the perspective of technical terms
# 一来应聘 家常菜
Come to apply for home cooking
# 其实我们真正的专业厨师
Actually our real professional chefs
# 还要从一个菜系学习
Also learn from a cuisine style
# 比如我喜欢川菜
For example, I like Sichuan food
# 粤菜
Cantonese food
# 淮扬菜
Huaiyang Cuisine
# 鲁菜
Lu Cai
# 一定要从一个菜系学习
Must learn from a cuisine style
# 然后旁通
Then extend your knowledge to others
# 学习一些其它菜系
Learn some other cuisines
# 这样自己就有一个
So you have a
# 最基本的本菜系的功底
basic skills of the cuisine
# 然后把它学精学透
Then learn it thoroughly
# 有必要 有时间到当地
It is necessary when you have time to go to the local
# 要考察当地的风土人情
To investigate the local customs
# 和人家那边的特产
And their specialties
# 还要了解人家生活习惯
Also understand local people's living habits
# 一些口味
Some flavors
# 因为现在地方的口味
Because of the local taste
# 也是不断的变化
Also constantly changing
# 所以他们要有一个定位 很多菜
So they have to have a positioning, many dishes
# 我和二伯在做菜的某一环节
Me and Er Bai are in a certain part of cooking
# 它是有根据的
It doesn’t come from nowhere
# 以前的麻婆豆腐
Mapo Tofu in the traditional way
# 就是搁牛肉的
Is using beef
# 牛肉末
Ground beef
# 有的单位可能为了
Someone may because
# （嫌）牛肉贵改成猪肉了
(They think) Beef was expensive then changed to pork
# 如果像这样改的话
If you change like this
# 到一代人 就十二年以后
Twelve years later in one generation
# 十年以上的
More than ten years
# 都会影响一批人
Will affect a group of people
# 从这他就认识到 麻婆豆腐
From then on he realized Mapo Tofu
# 可能以后就是猪肉
Maybe it will be pork from now on
# 跟牛肉没关系
It has nothing to do with beef
# 做菜当中你看有的专业厨师
You see some professional chefs in cooking
# 他那个不叫宫保鸡丁
He is not called Kung Pao Chicken
# 他只能叫炒三丁炒四丁
He can only call fried three diced fried four diced
# 但是他搁点辣椒
But he put some chili
# 搁点土豆
Put some potatoes
# 搁点胡萝卜
Some carrots
# 搁点鸡丁
Put some chicken
# 他就叫宫保鸡丁
He call it Kung Pao Chicken
# 所以像这种误导
So misleading like this
# 会影响一大批人
Will affect a large number of people
# 所以说传承一定要有根据
So the inheritance must have a basis
# 有些它一传200年300年
Some have been passed down for 200 years and 300 years
# 一直流传到现在经久不衰
It has been passed down to the present for a long time
# 那就是经过几代人的这种守旧
That’s how old-fashion get passed down after generations
# 守着传承不守旧
Keeping the inheritance
# 创新不忘本
Innovate with tradition in mind
# 好嘞
Here we go